Oscar Forner Martinez

I am a software engineer with experience in all phases of the development process with special focus on delivering quality software to the costumers. I have experience in a diversity of projects ranging from a RESTful API processing thousands of requests per second, through compilers to video processing pipelines.

You can use an interactive version of my CV by running: docker run -it maitesin/resume

Experience

April 2020

Lead Software Engineer at Paack

- Present

During my time in Paack I have worked in the Warehouse Management System, a new platform to allow parcels to be scanned and assigned to routes in a timely fashion. Moreover, I lead the revamp of the Business Rules Management System, a platform to allow Product People to change the rules applied to deliveries without having to change code. During this rework the whole architecture of the system changed, and a new UI was developed to fulfill the new requirements. I also had to design and implement the migration process for the system to avoid downtime.

As part of my role as Lead Software Engineer I mentored several people in my team and I was heavily involved in the hiring process of the company.

June 2018 - April 2020

Senior Backend Software Engineer at GlobalSign

As part of my duties in GlobalSign I implemented new functionalities in the **High Performance Platform** that serve thousands of certificates per second, and I took care of the migration of backend storage from **MongoDB** to **PostgreSQL**.

Moreover, I implemented a prototype of the system used in production running in **Kubernetes** to test the feasibility of a future migration. As a side project I developed an **static analysis** tool to enforce the code style used in the company.

I mentored multiple new-hires and had a highly involved role in the hiring process.

Sept. 2016 - June 2018

Software Engineer at VCA Technology

During my time at VCA Technology I created a **network library** that allows the user to interact with **Boost ASIO** through the **std::stream** interface, added **authentication** to the system, and designed the **configuration migration process**.

In addition, I improved the in-house **toolchain** to use **clang-tidy** for the linting of our code and I lead the usage of **continuous integration** in order to improve the product delivered to the customer, and to reduce the time to market.

April 2015

Software Developer at Programming Research

- Sept. 2016

I worked in two projects during my time at Programming Research.

- -Static analysis of code: Checks if the code has some patterns such as: *undefined behaviour*, *unspecified in the Standard*, and/or *implementation-defined*.
- -Dataflow analysis of code: Checks the complexity of methods, pointer problems, memory handling, etc.

July 2013

Software Engineer at European Bioinformatics Institute

- Apr. 2015

My main duty was to create a RESTful service to allow users to query for information about multiprotein complexes.

In addition, I developed an algorithm to cluster biological information from proteins.

2013-Present

Open Source

I am actively contributing to open source projects that I find interesting and useful. Some of my contributions can be found in my **GitHub profile**.

These include, YAUS, Yet Another URL Shortener is a toy project to play with Flask and Heroku, ARM C Compiler (ACC) is a self-hosting compiler for C in the ARM architecture, and Interactive CV built using Rust and Docker.

Education

2010-2013 Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science; Universitat Jaume I (Spain)

Advanced Data Structures, Compilers and Interpreters and Distributed Systems

2006-2010 Associate Degree in Computer Science; Universitat Jaume I (Spain)

Operating Systems, Real Time Operating Systems and Embedded Systems

Programming Languages

Python 5 years of experience.

C++ 5 years of experience using *Modern C*++ and *Boost*.

C 4 years of experience.

Go 4 years of experience.

Technical Skills

Build CMake, Meson, Make and Ninja.

CI GitLab-CI, Jenkins, Bamboo and Travis.

Databases MongoDB, PostgreSQL, SQLite, MariaDB and MySQL.

Analysis Golint, Go vet, Perf, Clang-sanitizer and Valgrind.

Orchestra. Docker compose, Heroku, Kubernetes and Helm.

Broker RabbitMQ, Redis and Kafka.

Languages

Spanish Native

English Fluent

oscar.forner.martinez@gmail.com +34 617 60 60 12

Blog: https://oscarforner.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/oscarforner

GitHub: https://github.com/maitesin